A Guide to the University of Virginia Division of Continuing Education General records, School and Community Drama Service, 1925-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia, Division of Continuing Education, School and Community Drama Service, General records 1925-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-16/2/3.871
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was an internal archival transfer, 1987 March 2.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of general records, School and Community Drama Service, Division of Continuing Education, including correspondence, photographs, book orders, reading lists, printed newsletters from other institutions and Southeastern Theatre Conference records (chiefly correspondence).
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence- General (6 folders), 1954-1958 (Folder 1)
  - Correspondence- Colleges and Universities, 1957-1958 (Folder 1)
  - Correspondence- Lending Program (Sample) (5 folders), 1954-1959, Originally 1.4 linear feet; one sample folder was retained from each year and the remainder was discarded. (Folder 1)
- Series II: General Records
  - Annual Report, 1934-1952 (Folder 1)
  - Bibliography- Dramatic Arts Course, 1950 (Folder 2)
  - Debate Library, 1971-1972 (Folder 2)
  - Deposit Slips, 1949-1956 (Folder 2)
  - Photographs (Arms and the Man), 1954 (Folder 2)
  - Photographs- One Act Play Festival (2 folders), 1956-1957 (Folder 2)
  - Photographs- Unidentified, 1955 (Folder 2)
  - Photographs- Unidentified, n.d. (Folder 2)
- Series III: South Eastern Theatre Conference
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Agenda, Executive Secretary- Treasures Report, 1957 (Folder 2)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Alabama, 1956-1957 (Folder 2)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- ANTA (2 folders), 1957 (Folder 2)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Ballew, Leighton, 1955-1958 (Folder 2)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Barter Theatre, 1956-1957 (Folder 2)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- John Caldwell, 1957-1958 (Folder 2)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Children's Theatre, 1956-1957 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Community Theatre, 1956-1957 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Constitution and By-Laws, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Convention (2 folders), 1957-1958 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Randolf Edwards, 1955-1957 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Florida, 1956-1958 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Georgia, 1954-1957 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Green, Paul (Bound Volume), 1957 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Green Celebration, 1957 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Kentucky, 1956-1958 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Fred Koch, 1955-1958 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Mailing Lists, 1956-1957 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Memberships (6 folders), 1950-1958 (Folder 3)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Memberships (2 folders), 1955-1957 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Minutes, 1955-1957 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Mississippi, 1956-1957 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Newsletter (2 folders), 1955-1956 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- North Carolina, 1956-1957 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- North Carolina Foundations, 1956-1957 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Patterson, Thomas M., 1954-1958 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Past Accounts, 1955 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Poag, Thomas, 1956-1957 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Popovich, 1957 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Porterfield, Robert, 1955-1957 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Professional Theatre, 1956-1957 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Selden, Paul (2 folders), 1955-1958 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- South Carolina, 1955-1958 (Folder 4)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- South Western Theatre Conference, 1957 (Folder 5)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Virginia (2 folders), 1956-1958 (Folder 5)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- West Virginia, 1956-1957 (Folder 5)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- Wright, Joseph, 1956-1957 (Folder 5)
  - South Eastern Theatre Conference- John W. Young, 1956-1957 (Folder 5)
- Series IV: Printed Matter
  - Alabama, University of, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Arizona, University of, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Bowling Green State University (Ohio), 1949-1951 (Folder 5)
  - Colorado State University, 1942 (Folder 5)
  - Cornell University (2 folders), 1941-1942 (Folder 5)
  - Cornell University (2 folders), 1955-1957 (Folder 6)
  - Other Extension Divisions (material form), 1953 (Folder 6)
  - Delaware, University of, 1946-1956 (Folder 6)
  - Florida, University of, 1939 (Folder 6)
  - Iowa, University of, 1950-1959 (Folder 6)
  - Illinois, University of, 1956 (Folder 6)
  - Indiana, University of, 1935 (Folder 6)
  - John Hopkins University, 1953 (Folder 6)
  - Kansas, University of, 1950 (Folder 7)
  - Kent State University, 1959 (Folder 7)
  - Miami, University of, 1948-1949 (Folder 7)
  - Kentucky, University of, 1959 (Folder 7)
  - Michigan, University of, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - Minnesota, University of, 1947-1959 (Folder 7)
  - North Carolina, University of, 1918-1958 (Folder 7)
  - Missouri, University of, 1948-1958 (Folder 7)
  - Murry State Teachers Colleges, 1946-1947 (Folder 7)
  - New Mexico, University of, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - Northwestern University, 1937-1946 (Folder 7)
  - Ohio State University, 1959 (Folder 8)
  - Oklahoma A. & M. College, 1937-1940 (Folder 8)
  - South Carolina, University of, 1955-1957 (Folder 8)
  - Tennessee, University of, 1943-1956 (Folder 8)
  - Texas, University of, 1950-1959 (Folder 8)
  - Washington, State College of, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - West Virginia, University of, 1945 (Folder 8)
  - Western Reserve University, 1941 (Folder 8)
  - Wisconsin, University of, 1955-1959 (Folder 8)